<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: books | Blog for Adam Fortuna]]></title>
  <link href="http://adamfortuna.com/tags/books/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://adamfortuna.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-09T00:26:33-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://adamfortuna.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Adam Fortuna]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Audiobook Habit]]></title>
    <link href="http://adamfortuna.com/audiobooks/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-14T12:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://adamfortuna.com/audiobooks</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There are so many (good) podcasts out there it&rsquo;s easy to get swept away by them. About 2 years ago I was subscribing to over 30 of them, many of them news that overlapped with each other. Around this time, I decided to take a break from podcasts and binge listen to all 5 Game of Thrones books. For reference, that&rsquo;s over 200 hours of content.</p>

<p>After about 2 month of audiobooks, I switched back to podcasts and found I was able to unsubscribe from nearly everything and wonder why I listened to many of them in the first place. After that, what I listened to changed dramatically &mdash; focusing on storytelling, education and entertainment rather than news.</p>

<p>Stopping this deluge of information in podcast form was similar to when I stopped reading RSS feeds (thanks Google Reader for going away!). It was information I didn&rsquo;t know I didn&rsquo;t need.</p>

<h2>Habit Forming</h2>

<p>I have a tendency to take things to the extreme. Why do something if you&rsquo;re not going to go all the way? Marilyn knows that whenever we&rsquo;re watching a TV show, we&rsquo;re not going to just watch one episode, we&rsquo;re going to watch the entire series from episode 1, in order.</p>

<p>This same tendency that can cause a lot of wasted time when listening to podcasts, actually helps out for marathoning audiobooks. From when I wake up in the morning and roll out of bed, if I&rsquo;m not talking to someone, programming, reading or watching TV, I&rsquo;m probably listening to an audiobook. People around the office have no doubt seen me walking around with earbuds in. This resulted in 45 books in <a href="/books/#/?readAfter=2013-01-01&amp;readBefore=2014-01-01">2013</a> and 39 books (so far) in <a href="http://adamfortuna.com/books/#/?readAfter=2014-01-01&amp;readBefore=2015-01-01">2014</a>.</p>

<h3>Podcasts</h3>

<p><div class='pull-right '><p>We started a <a href="http://instagram.com/p/wOq3osBzGu/">Cereal and Serial</a> listening club at work for the Serial Podcast.</p>
</div></p>

<p>I have missed out on some amazing podcasts in that time, and there are a few I&rsquo;ll still make sure to listen to. Freakanomics, RadioLab and Serial (for example) are all amazing, as well as too many others. Rather than tuning in each week for most of these (ie, all but Serial), I&rsquo;ll let them pile up then binge listen to 3-6 months of backlog in a few days. For other podcasts, I&rsquo;ll only pickout the episodes I like where they&rsquo;re touching on topics of interest, rather than listening to every episode regardless.</p>

<p>Seems obvious enough to do this, but when you&rsquo;re the habit of watching every episode of a TV show, skipping an episode of a podcast seems like you&rsquo;re not getting the full picture.</p>

<h2>Positive Implications</h2>

<p>What did this change have on my life? It wasn&rsquo;t immediately apparent, but a few things stand out. By tuning out tech gadget podcasts, I noticed my consumerist tendencies declined. By stopping some of the financial podcasts, I worried about investments less which resulted in less shifting money around and ultimately a more successful <a href="http://www.bogleheads.org/">Bogleheads</a> style strategy. By not tuning in on specific days each week for news, I had a less structured listening schedule where I wasn&rsquo;t immediately listening to whatever was available, and instead choosing what to listen to.</p>

<p><div class='pull-left '><p><a href="/books/#/books/0812993012"><img src="http://images.amazon.com/images/P/0812993012.01.ZTZZZZZZ.jpg" alt="Creativity Inc" /></a>&lt;/p&gt;</p>

<p><em>Creativity Inc</em>, 2014
</p>
</div></p>

<p>Listening around the house has helped me stay on track while getting things done. My entire garage was reorganized during a listen of <a href="http://adamfortuna.com/books/#/books/0380508567">Foundation</a>. <a href="http://adamfortuna.com/books/#/books/1583333894">Unstuff your Life</a> kickstarted a house cleanup that still proud of. <a href="http://adamfortuna.com/books/#/books/0812993012">Creativity Inc</a> began an amazing conversation at Code School that resulted in some effective changes to the way we work. <a href="http://adamfortuna.com/books/#/books/0307352145">Quiet: The Power of Introverts</a> was a interesting look at what gives me energy and helps drive me (and is a book I wish I had been able to read in middle school).</p>

<h3>Development</h3>

<p>The drive for additional data on what I was reading led to the creation of an Ember.js Application for managing them, as well as a Code School course on what I learned building it. Lately, my obsession has been AngularJS, and I have learned a huge amount re-implementing it in the new framework. The next step is some crazy data visualizations using D3, which I&rsquo;m exited to have some data available to experiment with. If anyone wants to hack on it with me, the code is public on GitHub at <a href="https://github.com/adamfortuna/scribe">adamfortuna/scribe</a>.</p>

<p>The inspiration for the books app was inspired by a few fellow programmers who have done the same. <a href="http://sivers.org/book">Derek Sivers</a> tracks what he&rsquo;s read, and tends to read business and personal improvement books. <a href="http://www.pamelafox.org/readinglist">Pamela Fox</a>, a fellow programmer in the education space, also tracks her books (we share a distaste for Neuromancer). Any other programmers out there do the same?</p>

<h2>Recommendations</h2>

<p><div class='pull-left '><p><a href="/books/#/books/0553283685"><img src="http://images.amazon.com/images/P/0553283685.01.ZTZZZZZZ.jpg" alt="Hyperion" /></a>&lt;/p&gt;</p>

<p><em>Hyperion</em>, 1989
</p>
</div></p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re looking for recommendations, the easiest thing is to checkout which books I&rsquo;ve rated as 5-star on <a href="http://goodreads.com">Goodreads</a> using the handy <a href="/books/#/?rating=5">books</a> page. 3 Books I recommend to everyone (although completely different in nature) are <a href="/books/#/books/030788743X">Ready Player One</a>, <a href="/books/#/books/0553283685">Hyperion</a> and <a href="/books/#/books/0765326353">The Stormlight Archive Series</a> (the last being the Fantasy equivalent of Game of Thrones &mdash; minus the sex).</p>

<p>On a side note, many thanks to <a href="https://twitter.com/adamrensel">Adam Rensel</a> for the continued amazing book recommendations! If anyone else has suggestions, I&rsquo;m all ears. Lately I&rsquo;ve been eying the <a href="http://www.npr.org/2011/08/11/139085843/your-picks-top-100-science-fiction-fantasy-books">NPR Top 100 Scienve Fiction and Fantasy</a> list as a good reference point, as well as <a href="/images/books/nprtop100.jpg">this amazing visualization</a> of which ones to focus on. The <a href="/books">books</a> page also shows what I&rsquo;m reading on the right, by tapping into GoodReads &ldquo;currently reading&rdquo; indicator.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reading List]]></title>
    <link href="http://adamfortuna.com/reading-list-74/"/>
    <updated>2006-12-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://adamfortuna.com/reading-list-74</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Lately I&rsquo;ve been negligent to my web projects in exchange for spending time reading. Unfortunately the distractions of blogs, digg, email and daily life have made this a slower process than I initially planned, but understanding how much time is spent on these things is the first step towards changing it. A while ago I moved my television out of the computer room, and I noticed an increase in my productivity. Similarly there&rsquo;s a room in the house now that has no television or computer which can be an excellent reading room. It&rsquo;s almost sad to think the time we spend as little kids watching TV repeating in this day with time spent repeatedly checking RSS feeds, Digg, Slashdot and email. One of my new years resolutions (which I&rsquo;m slowly phasing in) is to try to limit this unproductive online time. First step is to thin out my Google Reader down from it&rsquo;s unmanageable 89 feeds (!). Not too many have daily postings, but &ldquo;LifeHacker&rdquo;:<a href="http://lifehacker.com">http://lifehacker.com</a> , &ldquo;TechCruch&rdquo;:<a href="http://techcrunch.com">http://techcrunch.com</a> , &ldquo;SlashDot&rdquo;:<a href="http://slashdot.org">http://slashdot.org</a> and &ldquo;Joel.Reddit.com&rdquo;:<a href="http://joel.reddit.com">http://joel.reddit.com</a> are definitely staying on. What&rsquo;s on my reading list right now?</p>

<p>h3. Head First Design Patterns</p>

<p>!(left)http://adamfortuna.com/media/books/design_patterns.jpg! This is one of the best written programming books I have ever read, and has made me a true believer in O'Reily&rsquo;s Head First series. The main feature of this series of books is that they put emphasis not on having a reference book, but on you learning the topics down cold. In the introduction there is a description of studies done on how people learn- &ndash; through multiple ways. This series uses this combination of ways to both drive topics into peoples minds and keep readers interested. I can&rsquo;t remember a time when I was looking forward to reading a technical book (well yeah, maybe Pragmatic Programmer).</p>

<p>h3. UML Distilled: A Brief Guide to the Standard Object Modeling Language</p>

<p>!(right)http://adamfortuna.com/media/books/uml.jpg!:<a href="http://www.amazon.com/UML-Distilled-Standard-Modeling-Language/dp/0321193687/sr=1-2/qid=1165736128/ref=pd_bbs_sr_2/102-9962947-6835328?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books">http://www.amazon.com/UML-Distilled-Standard-Modeling-Language/dp/0321193687/sr=1-2/qid=1165736128/ref=pd_bbs_sr_2/102-9962947-6835328?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books</a> Getting into OOP, UML seemed the logical choice to study up on next. Some of the diagrams in Head First Design Patterns would have been more clear to me with the _ shared language_ or UML.</p>

<p>h3. Head First Object-Oriented Analysis and Design: A Brain Friendly Guide to Ooa&amp;d</p>

<p>!(left)http://adamfortuna.com/media/books/oo_design.jpg!:<a href="http://www.amazon.com/Head-First-Object-Oriented-Analysis-Design/dp/0596008678/sr=1-1/qid=1165736369/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1/102-9962947-6835328?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books">http://www.amazon.com/Head-First-Object-Oriented-Analysis-Design/dp/0596008678/sr=1-1/qid=1165736369/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1/102-9962947-6835328?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books</a> Along the same lines as above, but another take on it. I probably would have read this first, but I&rsquo;d already started UML Distilled before I knew of this one.</p>

<p>h3. Code Complete</p>

<p>!(right)http://adamfortuna.com/media/books/code_complete.jpg!:<a href="http://www.amazon.com/Code-Complete-Second-Steve-McConnell/dp/0735619670/sr=1-1/qid=1165736860/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1/102-9962947-6835328?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books">http://www.amazon.com/Code-Complete-Second-Steve-McConnell/dp/0735619670/sr=1-1/qid=1165736860/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1/102-9962947-6835328?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books</a></p>

<p>Along with Pragmatic Programmer and Joel on Software, this is one that I hear being recommended for programmers by a variety of people. Really looking forward to this one.</p>

<p>h3. Patterns of Enterprise Application Architecture</p>

<p>!(left)http://adamfortuna.com/media/books/patterns_architecture.jpg!:<a href="http://www.amazon.com/Patterns-Enterprise-Application-Architecture-Martin/dp/0321127420/sr=1-12/qid=1165737052/ref=sr_1_12/102-9962947-6835328?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books">http://www.amazon.com/Patterns-Enterprise-Application-Architecture-Martin/dp/0321127420/sr=1-12/qid=1165737052/ref=sr_1_12/102-9962947-6835328?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books</a> Sadly I started this book before getting distracted with Head First Patterns. I&rsquo;ve enjoyed Martin Fowlers style of writing though, so this and UML design are both fun reads. If I&rsquo;m still impressed when I finish them I might dive into MF&rsquo;s Refactoring as well.</p>

<p>Some of these books directly apply to things I&rsquo;m working on, but for the most part they are just general knowledge that&rsquo;s beneficial. There are some more direct things to read though, like &ldquo;Fusion Authority&rdquo;:<a href="http://www.fusionauthority.com/">http://www.fusionauthority.com/</a> and the &ldquo;Coldfusion MX 7 Study Guide&rdquo;:<a href="http://www.amazon.com/Macromedia-ColdFusion-Certified-Developer-Study/dp/0321330110/sr=1-4/qid=1165737455/ref=sr_1_4/102-9962947-6835328?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books">http://www.amazon.com/Macromedia-ColdFusion-Certified-Developer-Study/dp/0321330110/sr=1-4/qid=1165737455/ref=sr_1_4/102-9962947-6835328?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books</a> ( I want to get CF certified after all :). I&rsquo;d love to read up more on Spring and Aspect Oriented programming too somewhere along the lines. In the end though, books are all just support, it&rsquo;s what we do with the knowledge from them that&rsquo;s important, so I&rsquo;m sure I&rsquo;ll work in some programming time along the way as well.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Programming Update]]></title>
    <link href="http://adamfortuna.com/programming-update/"/>
    <updated>2006-02-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://adamfortuna.com/programming-update</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>bq. There is a delight in working in such a tractable medium. The programmer, like the poet, works only slightly removed from pure thought-stuff. He builds his castles in the air, from air, creating by exertion of the imagination. Few media of creation are so flexible, so easy to polish and rework, so readily capable of realizing grand conceptual structures. &ndash; The Mythical Man-Month</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve been reading quite a lot more lately, the above quote being one I just started tonight. Good break when you&rsquo;ve hit a snag in a project and need to clear your head a little. Development on personal projects is going pretty well too. The most annoying part though is that I&rsquo;m trying to do things the <em>right</em> way in a language I&rsquo;ve never used before; which makes development agonizingly slow at times. Lots of time reading the documentation and googling for examples, let me tell you. But when it works it&rsquo;s a great feeling. Database design is complete for phase 1, which will not include anywhere near all the features I have planned, but enough to build off. Not really putting a timeframe on the project as whole, just as long as I keep working on it I&rsquo;m content. Eventually I&rsquo;ll snap a picture of my sticky-note/whiteboard of the sitemap/structure; once I get a new camera. This thursday there&rsquo;s a Ruby On Rails meeting at the &ldquo;Orlando Java Users Group&rdquo;:<a href="http://www.orlandojug.org/">http://www.orlandojug.org/</a> all of us at work are going to check out too, so looking forward to that boosting my motivation a notch or two.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
